TINA CAI **UX DESIGNER**

ABOUT

UX designer with experience in user interaction design and front-end web development.

Skilled in communicating with project stakeholders, balancing their needs, and designing solutions within multidisciplinary teams. Committed to tackling problems with a user-centered approach through design thinking and retrospective.

CONTACT



Seattle, Washington, USA



(206) 407-4205



tinacai.me



linkedin.com/tinacai97



tinacai1997@gmail.com

SKILLS

Competitive Analysis

User Research

Persona Development

Information Architecture

Sketching / Wireframing

Prototyping

Storyboarding

Usability Testing

Visual Design

Style Guides

UI Animation

Responsive Web Design

HTML / CSS / JavaScript

TOOLS

Figma

Adobe CC

Sketch

Balsamiq

Visual Studio Code

GitHub

PROJECTS

Payd, E-Wallet App

Jun 2021 - Oct 2021

UX/UI Design | tinacal.me/payd.html

- Designed an e-wallet app that compiled mobile payment user goals into one platform, reducing the need for multiple financial apps.
- Conducted competitive analyses and user interviews to understand ewallet user needs, resulting in user personas and flows that represented app target audience.
- Tested design solutions with end-users to iterate on 30+ high fidelity wireframes, leading to an interactable prototype and style guide that presented a solution to an all-in-one e-wallet application.

Lingually, Language Learning App

May 2021 - Jun 2021

UX/UI Design | tinacai.me/lingually.html

- Designed a language app to motivate language learners to practice based on their needs, resulting in a versatile educational tool.
- Researched existing language apps and conducted user interviews to develop a user persona to empathize with and design towards.
- Created a low fidelity prototype then assessed it by performing usability tests on app functionality with end-users, leading to improved wireframes ready for mid-fidelity.

EXPERIENCE

Electrical Engineer

Jan 2020 - Apr 2021

Arup | Seattle, WA

- Designed electrical power systems based on client needs and available equipment and supply to new and existing buildings, producing electrical power and lighting plans for 13 building projects.
- Collaborated with project stakeholders on a regular basis to balance working on multidisciplinary projects, delivering 100+ deliverables on time and moving projects to the next design phase.

Electrical Engineering Intern

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

KATERRA | Seattle, WA

- Designed electrical power and lighting plans for a three 4-story multifamily residential project, successfully seeing a project design deliverable through and on time.
- Coordinated with internal architects and project members to modify electrical plans based on owner needs, room layout, and standards, resulting in a design package of 80+ code compliant drawings.

EDUCATION

User Experience Design Certificate

May 2021 - Dec 2021

CareerFoundry | Online Bootcamp

Front End Specialization

B.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

University of Washington | Seattle, WA

Power Design Concentration